You can hear me there? All of you?
شما آنجا صدای مرا می‌شنوید؟ همه شما؟
Those you can't hear me raise your hand
آنها که صدای مرا نمی‌شنوند دستانشان را بالا بگیرند.
Alright! thank you
خیلی خوب، ممنون.
So you better sing one song
پس بهتر است یک آواز بخوانید.
I'm sorry ,they told me now that people waiting
من متاسفم، آنها الان به من گفتند که مردم منتظر هستند.
"The Music of Joy" "Ayi Singha Pe Sawar, Maiya"
"The Music of Joy" "Ayi Singha Pe Sawar, Maiya"
Very nice to see you all so happy here.
بسیار خوشحالم که می‌بینم همه شما اینجا این‌قدر شاد هستید.
Today is the second day
امروز روز دوم است
and is a very important day from the point of evolution.
و از نظر تکاملی روز بسیار مهمی است.
As you know that our second chakra is very important.
همان‌طور که می‌دانید، دومین چاکرای ما بسیار مهم است،
That's why today is very important.
برای همین است که امروز روز بسیار مهمی است.
So what is the second chakra?
خوب دومین چاکرا چیست؟
Do you know which one is the second chakra?
آیا می‌دانید دومین چاکرا چیست؟
Ah? What did they say?
ها؟ آنها چه گفتند؟
You must tell loudly.
شما باید بلند بگویی!
Swadisthan is the chakra, is very important because
این چاکرا سوادیستان است، خیلی مهم است
in this Kali Yuga, Swadisthana works the most.
چون در این کالی‌یوگا، سوادیستانا بیشتر از همه کار می‌کند.
We have so many agents to make it work
ما ماموران بسیار زیادی داریم که آن را وادار می‌کنند
to make it work and work very hard.
کار کند و خیلی سخت کار کند.
You know what is in second chakra.
شما می‌دانید در چاکرای دوم چیست.
In the second chakra what happens
در دومین چاکرا چه اتفاقی می‌افتد؟
that we are caught up by our ambition
این که ما گرفتار جاه‌طلبی‌هایمان می‌شویم
and the ambition makes you run up and down,
و این جاه‌طلبی باعث می‌شود دائم بالا پایین بدوید
and I've seen many Sahaja Yogis also getting lost,
و من بسیاری از ساهاجایوگی‌ها را دیده‌ام که گمراه شده‌اند.
so it's a very important day for all of you.
پس امروز برای همه شما روز بسیار مهمی است.
So second chakra is important because
پس چاکرای دوم مهم است؛ چرا که
in modern times it is very, very
در دوران مدرن، این چاکرا بسیار فراگیر و فعال شده است.
We become very active, over active,
ما بسیار فعال می‌شویم، بیش فعال می‌شویم
and we start thinking about everyone with whom we are not concerned
و شروع می‌کنیم به فکر کردن به هر شخصی که از نظر ما اهمیتی ندارد،
and bothering our heads.
و مغزمان را اذیت می‌کنیم.
So today's chakra is important because it bothers your head,
پس چاکرای امروز مهم است چون مغز شما را اذیت می‌کند،
it troubles you a lot
شما را خیلی آزار می‌دهد!
and you start thinking about them.
و شما هم مشغول فکر کردن به آنها می‌شوید.
You start thinking what have you said, what has happened,
شروع می‌کنید فکر کردن که چه گفتید، چه اتفاقی افتاد،
who is angry, all sorts of nonsense.
چه کسی عصبانی است و همه نوع مزخرفاتی!
You are all Sahaja yogis,
شما همه ساهاجایوگی هستید؛
so you shouldn't worry as to all these people,
پس شما نباید نگران هیچ یک از این افراد باشید
what they say, what they are doing.
که آنها چه می‌گویند، آنها چه می‌کنند.
You should just enjoy yourself.
شما فقط باید از خودتان لذت ببرید.
Second chakra you must enjoy.
از چاکرای دوم باید لذت ببرید.
That's the best way to enjoy Sahaja Yoga.
این بهترین راه برای لذت بردن از ساهاجایوگا است.
Where your Swadisthana is satisfied
وقتی سوادیستانای شما راضی باشد،
nothing can destroy you or disturb you.
چیزی نمی‌تواند باعث نابودی یا پریشانی شما شود.
At Swadisthana you can really look after;
در سوادیستانا شما واقعا می‌توانید مراقبت کنید؛
Swadisthan Chakra is so much good for you because
چاکرای سوادیستانا برای شما خیلی خوب است چون
now you are Sahaja Yogis and you can master it.
الان شما ساهاجایوگی هستید و می‌توانید بر آن چیره شوید.
That is one chakra which upsets, especially in the West
آن یک چاکرایی است که ناراحت می‌کند، به خصوص در غرب،
people think too much, all the time
مردم خیلی فکر می‌کنند، دائم فکر می‌کنند،
thinking, thinking, thinking.
فکر می‌کنند و فکر می‌کنند.
That's from Swadisthan,
این از سوادیستان است.
you get that problem from Swadisthan.
شما از سوادیستان دچار آن مشکل می‌شوید.
To satisfy Swadisthan, you have to take to silence.
برای راضی کردن سوادیستان، شما باید به سکوت رو بیاورید.
You have to take to quietude and look at yourself.
شما باید به خاموشی رو بیاورید و به خودتان نگاه کنید.
What is bothering you, what is troubling you,
آنچه دارد شما را آزار می‌دهد، آنچه شما را به دردسر می‌اندازد،
what gives you ideas and thoughts
آنچه به شما ایده و فکر می‌دهد،
is Swadisthan.
سوادیستانا است.
And some people think so much.
و بعضی افراد خیلی زیاد فکر می‌کنند.
There may not be any problem,
شاید هیچ مشکلی در کار نباشد،
but they create their own problem with the Swadisthana
ولی آنها با سوادیستانا، مشکلات خودشان را ایجاد می‌کنند
and just go on bothering about the stuff.
و فقط مدام نگران این مسائل هستند.
Swadisthan is very happy
در صورتی سوادیستان خیلی خوشحال است
when you are just laughing and enjoying
که شما فقط بخندید و لذت ببرید
and not bothered about nonsense.
و نگران مزخرفات نباشید.
How much time we waste on nonsense!
چقدر ما سر مزخرفات وقت تلف می‌کنیم!
We don't need it,
ما به آن نیازی نداریم؛
Sahaja Yogis don't need it.
ساهاجایوگی‌ها نیازی به آن ندارند.
It's only those who are not yet realized
فقط آنها که هنوز خودآگاه نیستند،
must be suffering. They do suffer and they might even trouble you, but just laugh at it
حتما زجر می‌کشند و زجر هم می‌کشند و حتی ممکن است شما را هم اذیت کنند؛ ولی فقط به آن بخندید
and you must pardon them, forgive them, because they are doing this
و باید که آنها را عفو کنید، ببخشید. چون آنها این کار را می‌کنند
because they can't help it.
به خاطر این که چاره‌‌ای ندارند.
You see, this Swadisthan Chakra is bothering them
می‌دانید، این چاکرای سوادیستاناست که آنها را آزار می‌دهد؛
so they can't help it.
برای همین دست خودشان نیست.
You don't have space.
شما جا ندارید.
Come forward a little bit, poor man.
کمی بیایید جلوتر. بیچاره؛
I'm sorry.
ببخشید.
You can come forward, here there is seat,
شما می‌توانید بیایید جلو، اینجا جا هست،
some people make room for them.
بعضی‌هایتان برایشان جا باز کنید.
Ah good, and move forward, please.
ها، خوب است. بیاید جلو، لطفا.
You bring your harmonium and you come forward.
شما هارمونیومت را بیاور و بیا جلو.
Are you going to dance? Good.
شما می‌خواهی برقصی؟ خوب است.
So now, don't allow your mind
پس حالا، نگذارید ذهن شما
to bother about whatever nonsensical thoughts are coming
با هر فکر مزخرفی که می‌رسد به زحمت بیفتد،
- all kinds of, all kinds of nonsensical thoughts.
هر جور، هر جور فکر مزخرفی.
You have nothing to do with them, but the thoughts are coming
شما کاری به آنها ندارید، ولی فکرها می‌آیند.
Now, this is the work of Mister Swadisthan.
حالا این کار آقای سوادیستان است.
He's trying to distract you,
او سعی می‌کند حواس شما را پرت کند.
you must get into silence.
شما باید وارد سکوت شوید.
Once you get into silence,
وقتی وارد سکوت شدید،
then he will go away and don't bother you.
آن وقت او می‌رود و شما را اذیت نمی‌کند.
My all attention is on your country
همه توجه من به کشور شماست؛
because you're very good Sahaja Yogis.
چون شما ساهاجایوگی‌های بسیار خوبی هستید.
We have had Sahaja Yogis all over the world,
ما در سراسر جهان ساهاجایوگی داشته‌ایم،
you know in thousands they are,
می‌دانید که هزاران نفر هستند،
but nothing like Australian, I see.
ولی می‌بینم هیچ‌کدام مثل استرالیایی‌ها نمی‌شوند.
Because they are somehow or other very deeply touched
چون آنها به نوعی عمیقا تحت تاثیر و نگران مشکلات دنیا هستند.
So what you have to think now:
پس حالا به چه چیزی باید فکر کنید،
not to have anything to do with Swadisthan,
که کاری به سوادیستانا نداشته باشید.
but what you have to become
ولی به کسی باید تبدیل شوید
is you are Sahaja Yogis
که ساهاجایوگی باشد.
and no Swadisthan should bother you.
و هیچ سوادیستانایی نباید شما را آزار ‌دهد.
So there was … I never knew that you were all here,
بنابراین، من نمی‌دانستم شما همه اینجا بودید،
now only they told Me that you were all here.
تازه به من گفتند که شما اینجا هستید.
They said, "Only a few people are there."
آنها گفتند: "فقط چند نفر هستند."
I said, "All right."
من گفتم: "باشد."
Ah? How many? You have counted them?
ها؟ چند نفر؟ آنها را شمرده‌اید؟
Now, very sweet,
خوب، خیلی شیرینند!
Australia is really great to have beautiful children like this.
استرالیا واقعا فوق‌العاده است که چنین بچه‌های زیبایی دارد؛
And people care for children.
و افراد از بچه‌هایشان مراقبت می‌کنند.
That is first thing you must do is to care for your children.
این اولین کاری است که باید انجام دهید؛ که از بچه‌هایتان مراقبت کنید.
That is fighting your Swadisthan.
این جنگ با سوادیستانای‌تان است.
Anything bothers you,
هر وقت چیزی شما را آزار داد،
you worry about you own children, finished.
به فکر بچه‌هایتان بیفتید، تمام!
You have to bother about them and everything will work out.
شما باید نگران آنها باشید و همه چیز درست خواهد شد.
"What's the matter, are you not are all right?
"چه شده، حالت خوب نیست؟
You are all right?"
شما خوبی؟"
You are definitely blessed
شما به طور قطع مورد رحمت هستید؛
because you are not falling to the whims of your Swadisthan.
چون تسلیم هوا و هوس‌های سوادیستانا نمی‌شوید.
Definitely, and that is the chakra of your country also.
قطعا؛ و اینکه این چاکرا مال کشور شما هم هست.
So it makes you run up and down and think and think and think.
برای همین شما را به بالا و پایین دویدن و فکر کردن و فکر کردن و فکر کردن وادار می‌کند.
Especially all the Sahaja Yogis have this problem.
به خصوص همه ساهاجایوگی‌ها این مشکل را دارند.
So you should just think
پس فقط باید در نظر داشته باشید
that you are sitting on Swadisthan
که شما روی سوادیستان نشسته‌اید
and you have to ride it, not to be ridden by it. All right?
و باید که شما سوار آن باشید، نه این که آن سوار شما باشد.بسیار خوب؟
I'm so proud of you people from this country
من به شما بسیار افتخار می‌کنم؛ مردم این کشور راه را به دیگر مردم جهان نشان داده‌اند،
how can you be united and to be one.
این که چطور می‌شود متحد و یکی بود.
It's rather very surprising.
این واقعا حیرت‌انگیز است.
In other countries the problem is different.
در کشورهای دیگر، مشکلات متفاوتند.
Your country is the problem of Swadisthana as I said today,
مشکل این کشور همان‌طور که امروز گفتم سوادیستان است؛
but you people have conquered it.
ولی شما بر آن غلبه پیدا کرده‌اید.
When I came first year I found
سال اول که آمدم دیدم که
everybody's head moving with the Swadisthana.
اختیار همه به دست سوادیستانا است.
Then they became silent and very peaceful
آنها بعدا ساکت و بسیار آرام شدند
and now I see you all and I'm very happy
و حالا همه شما را می‌بینم و من بسیار خوشحالم؛
because that's gone now,
چون حالا او رفته
all that nonsense is finished.
و همه مزخرفات تمام شده است؛
And there is nothing bothers you.
و هیچ‌چیزی نیست که شما را نگران کند.
The root of all diseases is Swadisthan,
ریشه تمام بیماری‌ها سوادیستان است؛
it comes from there.
بیماری‌ها از آن ناشی می‌شوند.
So you should know not to play into hands of Swadisthan
پس باید بدانید که بازیچه دست سوادیستان نشوید
and go into thinking, thinking, thinking.
و مدام فکر نکنید و فکر نکنید و فکر نکنید.
They go on thinking, I mean something that doesn't exist,
آنها مرتب فکر می‌کنند، یعنی به چیزی که اصلا وجود خارجی ندارد،
they go on thinking.
همین‌طور فکر می‌کنند.
So any such thought comes in you said,
پس چنین فکرهایی اگر آمد بگویید:
"We don't want to think," finished.
"نمی‌خواهیم فکر کنیم"، تمام!
I'm there to think for you,
من هستم که برایتان فکر کنم؛
you don't think.
شما فکر نکنید.
If you have any problem, you let Me know,
هر مشکلی هست به من بگویید،
but you don't think.
ولی شما فکر نکنید.
What you can do, you can write it down and send the problems to Me
کاری که می‌توانید بکنید این است که آن را بنویسید و مشکلات را به من بفرستید.
and I would like to see it. All right?
و من مایلم آن را ببینم. باشد؟
And then Swadisthana is chakra of your country,
و بعد، سوادیستانا، چاکرای کشور شماست؛
that is the second chakra and is here.
که دومین چاکرا و اینجاست.
And you'll be amazed to know
و شگفت‌آور است که بدانید
that Sahaja Yogis there are from every country, but Australian ones are something special.
ساهاجایوگی‌ها، آنها از همه کشورها هستند؛ ولی استرالیایی‌ها چیزی استثنایی دارند.
They have very great faith in themselves.
آنها ایمان بسیار محکمی به خودشان دارند.
They do not go to wrong ideas.
آنها دنبال فکرهای اشتباه نمی‌روند.
I've seen that,
من این را دیده‌‌ام
and I am very much thankful to you for that.
و به این خاطر از شما بسیار متشکرم.
So what other song you want to sing? I would like to hear.
خوب چه آهنگ دیگری می‌خواهید بخوانید؟ می‌خواهم بشنوم.
"The Music of Joy" "Mata Oh Mata"
"The Music of Joy" "Mata Oh Mata"